<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on HKU Student Union</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on HKU Student Union</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 11:46:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HKU complicity in the ongoing genocide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/hkucomplicityintheongoinggenocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 11:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/hkucomplicityintheongoinggenocide/</guid>
      <description>About the complicity of the HKU and why this is still relevant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement about the new workshop policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/statementaboutthenewworkshoppolicy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:50:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/statementaboutthenewworkshoppolicy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of the 1st of September 2025, it will no longer be possible for alumni to use the workshops at the HKU. In the past, the rule was that this was allowed in the academic year immediately after your graduation. All students who are currently doing a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s, master&amp;rsquo;s or associate&amp;rsquo;s degree will no longer be able to use this arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cancellation of this arrangement was communicated to HKU students on the 1st of April via a short message on the Studentportal. This message states that the CvB (Executive Board) has taken this decision because (part of) the money that keeps the workshop running comes from the government. According to a government policy rule, this money may not be used for &amp;rsquo;external parties&amp;rsquo; (in this case, graduates). However, the policy rule has been in effect since 2022; it is unclear why this would only influence the CvB&amp;rsquo;s decision on the alumni arrangement now. It is also unclear why this policy rule would only affect the HKU; other universities of applied sciences (such as the KABK) still maintain a similar alumni arrangement. The CvB of the KABK seems to not have chosen to stop the rule for the use of workshops for their graduates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Racism in HKU</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/institutionalracisminhku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 11:57:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/institutionalracisminhku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November of last year, a teacher at HKU-Media resigned because of institutional racism. For years, this teacher experienced comments, questions, and a feeling of loneliness as one of the only teachers of colour. This led to them not feeling welcome at HKU. After years of futile attempts to shine a light on this injustice, they did not see another option other than to resign. The fact that an excellent teacher, and a pillar of support for students of colour, did not feel at home for years is utterly unforgivable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
